

#### **PROFILE**

A Result Driven Professional with +30 years of experience in TIC ( Testing, Inspection & Certification) Industry, Having excellent leadership skills, who exceeded revenue goals, increased market share , ensured business development and achieved high customer satisfaction.

Handled +85 Cr per year revenue across region including man management of +1000 HCs with improved market share YOY against competitors. Outstanding ability to complete Multiple tasks, having excellent administrative & Interpersonal skills. Talented at facilitating & improving Service delivery which results stronger professional relationships with clients Strong Believer of Quality Management, **Ethics** and treating People with Dignity.

#### CONTACT

PHONE: +91 9601285445

DOB 25.09.1969

EMAIL: sudhirvora20@gmail.com

## **HOBBIES**

Sports Travelling

# SUDHIR N VORA

Regional Branch Manager

#### **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

Bachelor of Science (Special) with chemistry as
 Principal subject from Gujarat University (1990)

### Professional Trainings:

2016 - E- Learning on Networking Capital

2011 - Interview & Selection for Managers.

2011 - Project Management Essentials

2011 - Finance for Non Financial Managers.

2011 - Managing People & Performance.

2010 - Customer Care From CIMCON.

 2008 - Post harvest Technology, Cold chain Management and Food Safety Issues (Supported by Indo-US Science & Technology forum and Sponsored by GOI, Ministry of food Processing)

2008 - Effective Selling

2008 - 5 S - Continuous Improvement Training

2007 - Sales, Marketing and Strategy Planning

2004 - Key Account Management, Mercury training by CIMCON

1999 - ISO & QMS Awareness Training.

1998 - Quality Management and controls in feed stuffs and export Certification.

1993 - Analysis of foods and feeds for Mycotoxins from CFTRI (Central Foods and Technological Research Institute ) Mysore.

## Achievements (2010 - 2021)

- √ Achieved Revenue Growth from about 21 Cr to +85 CR of Region.
- Crossed Statutory compliance level from 55% to +95% keeping margins undisturbed.
- ✓ Achieved QHSE compliances more than 85%.
- ✓ Closed labor specific legal matters from +16 to 9.
- √ Successfully lead Regional business BCM keeping uninterrupted during various calamities Natural e,g ,Cyclones, Floods with NIL casualty. Handled operations & Man management successfully during Severe C19 cycle.
- Successfully & Timely completed 3 CSR Projects worth investment of 73 Lakhs.

#### Achievements ( 2008 – 2010 )

- ✓ Improved & Achieved
  Technical compliance level
  from About 55% to nearly
  87% for all India locations
  by doing TG audits / Process
  Audits & Providing
  Necessary Training to
  Employees.
- ✓ Achieved Customer Feedback Across India by about 90%

#### Achievements ( 2005 – 2010 )

- Have Achieved Branch Revenue Growth from 1.5 Cr to 6 Cr without disturbing margins.
- √ Have Reduced DSO from +85 days to 50 days by aggressive collection Drives.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# SGS INDIA – REGIONAL BRANCH MANAGER (Gujarat & Rajasthan)

From - September 2010 - December -2021

**R-** Administering the region including Business Development, Statutory compliances, Effective Cost Management, QHSE Compliances, Labor Specific legal matters, Leading Business Continuity Management & CSR activities.

# SGS INDIA – National Quality Assurance & Technical Governance Auditor (Agri Trade Business ) From April 2008 – August -2010

**R-** Collaborate, Plan and complete Process Audits / Technical Governance audits at 11 Sea Ports / locations of India. Process involves to Check Chronic Process/Technical & Quality related issues, Train employees & suggest remedial actions to improve & achieve maximum compliance level. Collect Feedback from Clients & Prepare reports for Management Review.

### SGS INDIA – Branch Manager – (INDORE)

From September 2005 – August 2010.

**R** -Controlling Operational Territory of Madhya Pradesh, Chhattisgarh, Southern Rajasthan, Northern Maharashtra and Southern UP. Business Development, Planning & Controlling Branch activities including Job acquisition, Execution and Man Management of Agri, Industrial, Minerals & Textiles inspection business (+250 no)

#### SGS INDIA - Executive (Gandhidham)

From June 2000 - September 2005.

**R** -Job involves scrutinizing various inquiries, sending Quotations, reviewing & Execution of various EXIM orders, coordination with national and international clients. Issuing Final certificates, Invoices and timely collection of payment.

# SGS INDIA – Laboratory Incharges ( Agri, Minerals and OGC ) ( Gandhidham ) From – 1993 -2000

**R**- Job involves Right from Establishment of Laboratory, Method Devolopment with various international standards, testing of various Agri commodities, minerals, chemicals and petroleum products, preparation of various test procedures, development of new tests with reference to BIS. Administrations and Laboratory management.

# SGS INDIA - EXIM Inspections at Kandla Port. From April 1991 – 1993.

**R** -EXIM Inspections at Kandla Port Job involves inspections of chemicals, Minerals, Petroleum products & Agri products of reputed EXIM clients with extensive traveling in Gujarat and Rajasthan.

#### **SKILIS**



